<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string-array name="bmi">
        <item>
"You are underweight and hence following diet and exercises are prescribed.
Strength Training
One of the most important exercises you can do to start gaining weight is lifting weight. You want the weight you
gain to be muscle, rather than just fat. Increasing your caloric intake alone can help you increase body fat, but
 what you want is an even distribution of healthy fat and mostly muscle, and weightlifting and other strength
training exercises can help you achieve this.

Lifting weights is one type of strength training that can help you build muscle mass. You can start a
weightlifting program for beginners if you've never done it before. If you plan to use dumbbells at home, visit
a personal trainer first to learn proper form.

At the gym, there is also strength training equipment, such as lat machines. Ask a trainer at the gym to work with you
on learning proper form on these types of apparatus.
Diet Considerations:
If you want to gain weight, you'll need to eat a high-calorie diet without turning to unhealthy fats and sugars.
 Instead, aim for a variety of healthy foods, adding "good" fats into the mix more often than you may have previously
 done. Examples of good fats are avocados, nuts, and plant-based oils. Don't go overboard with the fats; a healthy
 diet includes everything in moderation.
Develop a reasonable exercise routine that includes both strength training and cardiovascular activities, and
pair these workouts with a healthy, varied diet. Calculate your ideal weight and then use diet and exercise in
 order to reach that weight and develop a healthy physique. While it may be tempting, if you are underweight, to
 forego exercise altogether, your body needs the cardiovascular exercise for overall physical and mental health
 and the strength training to prevent injuries. All healthy lifestyles include exercise; if you need help getting
 started, consult your doctor, a personal trainer, and a nutritionist for expert advice."
</item>
        <item>
"Congratulations you are in Normal weight category and to enjoy the good health
you must follow the following diet and exercises.
MAKE FRUITS AND VEGETABLES YOUR BEST FRIENDS- Eat fruits and veggies for good health!! ...
DRINK PLENTY OF WATER AND HERBAL TEAS- Drink enough water and have herbal teas! ...
STAY AWAY FROM REFINED AND PACKAGED FOODS- ...
DO NOT FORGET TO EAT A PROTEIN RICH MEAL- ...
CONSUME A SOUP BOWL BEFORE LUNCH AND DINNER"
</item>
        <item>
"You are Overweight and to lose weight you must follow the following diet
and exercises.
Workouts will help you to lose weight, can help you to change the way you feel about yourself, boost your mood, and improve your health.
Carrying too much excess weight puts you at higher risk for certain diseases, including high blood pressure, heart disease, diabetes, sleep apnea, and
depression. A program of moderate exercise can help you to reduce your risk of disease. Weight loss, which may happen as a result of exercise, can also
help to reduce your risk for disease.
Best Workouts for Obese Adults
These programs are particularly well suited for larger people who exercise.
1) Walking

This seems like an obvious choice, but there is a reason that walking tops the list of the best exercise for almost everyone. Walking requires very
 little equipment and it can be done almost everywhere. Walking is low impact, improves strength and mobility in the lower body, and can be easy, moderate,
 or vigorous depending on your specific plan.
Keep in mind, however, that walking isn't for everyone. If you experience knee, back, or hip pain, talk to your healthcare provider. You may be able to
 work with a physical therapist or exercise professional to address the issue or come up with a better routine for fitness.


2) Strength Training

There are many good reasons to start a strength training program. But for an overweight exerciser, there are special benefits.

Strength training can correct postural issues that may arise from carrying extra weight. Strength training can also increase the range of motion in all of
your joints. Finally, when you build muscle, you boost your metabolism when your body is at rest.
"
</item>

        <item>
"Heavens!! You are obese and you must seriously follow the following diet
and exercises to lead a healthy life.
Eat Well
Calories matter for weight-and some foods make it easier for us to keep our calories in check. Healthy eating is a key to good health as well as maintaining
a healthy weight. It’s not only what and how much we eat but also, it seems, how we eat that’s important.

What to Eat

Choose minimally processed, whole foods:

Whole grains (whole wheat, steel cut oats, brown rice, quinoa)
Vegetables (a colorful variety-not potatoes)
Whole fruits (not fruit juices)
Nuts, seeds, beans, and other healthful sources of protein (fish and poultry)
Plant oils (olive and other vegetable oils)
Drink water or other beverages that are naturally calorie-free.

Limit these foods and drinks:

Sugar-sweetened beverages (soda, fruit drinks, sports drinks)
Fruit juice (no more than a small amount per day)
Refined grains(white bread, white rice, white pasta) and sweets
Potatoes (baked or fried)
Red meat (beef, pork, lamb) and processed meats (salami, ham, bacon, sausage)
Other highly processed foods, such as fast food
A good example of an overall healthy diet is the Harvard School of Public Health’s Healthy Eating Pyramid and Healthy Eating Plate. The Nutrition Source, a
companion website to The Obesity Prevention Source, also offers a quick guide to choosing healthy drinks, as well as recipes and quick tips for eating right.


How Much to Eat

Age, gender, body size, and level of physical activity dictate how many calories you need each day to lose weight or to stay at a healthy weight. With two
out of three U.S. adults overweight or obese, it’s clear that many of us need to eat fewer calories.

Online calorie-needs calculators are a bit over-generous with their recommendations. And, in practice, it’s hard for people to track the amount of calories
 they take in each day.

A better approach: Adopt habits that will help you avoid overeating (see below)-and skip some of the high-calorie, low-nutrient foods that are most strongly
linked to weight gain, such as sugar-sweetened beverages, refined grains, and potatoes.

How to Avoid Overeating

Eat breakfast. While it seems like skipping a meal is an easy way to cut calories, skipping breakfast usually backfires when hunger comes raging back mid-day
, often leading to overeating.
Choose small portions and eat slowly. Slowing down at meals and choosing smaller portions can help avoid overeating by giving the brain time to tell the
stomach when it’s had enough food. Limiting distractions-turning off the television, computer, or smartphone-can also help us focus on the food.
Eat at home. Fast food, restaurant meals, and other foods prepared away from home tend to have larger portions and be less nutritious than the foods we cook
for ourselves.
Eat mindfully. Taking time to think about why you’re actually eating is an easy way to avoid needless calories. Hungry? Make the healthiest food and drink
 choices possible. Not really hungry? Choose something else to do or have a piece of fruit instead of a full meal. When you do eat, focus all of your senses
on the food, so that you can truly enjoy what you are eating. More information about mindful eating can be found at The Center for Mindful Eating and the
website for the book Savor: Mindful Eating, Mindful Life.
Stay Active"
</item>

    </string-array>
</resources>