<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string-array name="disease">
        <item>"COMMON COLD AND FLU"</item>
        <item>"DENGUE"</item>
        <item>"BRONCHITIS"</item>
        <item>"TONSILITIS"</item>
        <item>"SPRAIN"</item>
        <item>"DIABETES"</item>
        <item>"BLOOD PRESSURE"</item>
        <item>"DIARRHOEA"</item>
        <item>"GAS AND ACIDITY"</item>
        <item>"TUBERCULOSIS"</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="ddetails">
        <item>"Symptoms
1.Runny or Stuffy Nose
2.Sore throat
3.Sneezing
4.Cough
5.Headache or Body Aches
6.Mild Tiredness

Flu symptoms can include:
1.Dry, Hacking Cough
Moderate to High Fever(although not everyone with the flu will run a fever)
2.Sore Throat
3.Shaking Chills
4.Severe Muscle or Body Aches
5.Headache
6.Stuffy and Runny Nose
7.Severe Fatigue(may last up to two weeks)
8.Nausea and Vomiting (most common in children)

Remedies:
1.Drink Lots of Fluids
Good hydration helps moisturize the lining of the nose and throat, which makes mucus easier to clear. Aim to drink more fluids than usual. But be sure to avoid caffeinated or alcoholic drinks, as they can cause dehydration.

2. Use an Air Humidifier
You can also help keep nasal and throat passages moist by using an air humidifier, particularly in the winter months when heating makes the air inside your home very dry. Be sure to follow the instructions to keep it clean if you are using it infrequently.

3. Try a Neti Pot
Another way to prevent nasal dryness is with a neti pot, a nose-rinsing device found in drug and health-food stores (just make sure the device is clean and you’re using it properly to ensure that it’s safe and effective, according to the FDA). These pots are filled with a saline (salt water) solution and are inserted into one nostril while the user tilts his or her head to the side to allow the solution to flow up the nasal passage and out the other nostril.

4. Eat Chicken Soup
The adage about chicken soup being good for a cold is practically as old as the common cold itself. And there's some truth to what your grandmother has been telling you all these years. "Chicken soup is nice for the common cold because it loosens up your mucus," says Norman Edelman, MD, a professor of preventive medicine, internal medicine, and physiology and biophysics at the State University of New York at Stony Brook and a senior scientific adviser for the American Lung Association.

5. Take Echinacea
Evidence is mixed on the effects of echinacea on the common cold, but some experts say it can be helpful. "Echinacea does not prevent infection, but several studies have suggested that echinacea helps reduce the duration of upper respiratory infection symptoms," says Adriane Fugh-Berman, MD, a professor of pharmacology and physiology at Georgetown University Medical Center in Washington, DC.

6. Reach for Some Zinc Lozenges
Like echinacea, the mineral zinc gets mixed marks when being assessed for its effectiveness against the common cold. "I have not seen any evidence for prevention," says Dr. Fugh-Berman, "but there is some evidence — according to a review article published in the June 2013 issue of the Cochrane Database of Systematic Reviews — that zinc in the form of lozenges can decrease the symptoms of a common cold."

7. Take Vitamin C
It's up there with chicken soup as far as legendary cold remedies go, and there may be some truth to vitamin C's being helpful. Get it as a supplement or by upping your intake of vitamin C–rich foods, like citrus, green peppers, dark leafy greens, and kiwi fruit. Several studies show that it can reduce the duration and severity of a common cold, according to research published in January 2013 in the Cochrane Database of Systematic Reviews.

8. Give Your Nose a Massage
Try massaging the acupuncture point known as yingxiang, located at the lower border of the nostril. Scientific research on the effectiveness of this technique is limited, but an older, small study published in the American Journal of Rhinology did find that this type of nasal massage can provide relief from nasal congestion.

9. Gargle With Water
Research suggests that gargling with water three times a day can actually help prevent upper respiratory tract infections. So gargle away, before that common cold gets any worse.

10. Stock Your Medicine Cabinet
Not exactly a home remedy in the traditional sense, but there's no denying that over-the-counter (OTC) cold remedies — such as Tylenol (acetaminophen) or Mucinex (guaifenesin) — can provide temporary relief. The American Lung Association recommends that these medications be taken as soon as common cold symptoms arise. If you have high blood pressure, though, talk to your doctor about OTC cold medications you should avoid.

And of course, there's no substitute for eating right and getting plenty of rest to keep your immune system strong so that you're in prime shape to keep those colds at bay!"
</item>
        <item>"SYMPTOMS
1.Sudden, high fever
2.Severe headaches
3.Pain behind the eyes
4.Severe joint and muscle pain
5.Fatigue
6.Nausea
7.Vomiting
8.Skin rash, which appears two to five days after the onset of fever
9.Mild bleeding (such a nose bleed, bleeding gums, or easy bruising)

REMEDIES
Supportive care in a hospital
People suffering from severe effects must seek admission at their nearest hospital. Not only the sufferer and his family will get elaborate information about dengue, he/she will be under continuous observation and medications.

Intravenous (IV) fluid and electrolyte replacement
The Dengue Shock Syndrome causes severe abdominal pain, bleeding and circulatory collapse, accompanied by blueness around the mouth, blood in the stool, spots of blood in the skin, spitting up of blood, bleeding gums and bleeding of the nose. The affected should be rushed to the intensive care unit for a central intravenous line for volume replacement.

Blood pressure monitoring
Monitoring the blood pressure is an intensive part of the treatment as it provides an accurate information about the pressure of blood in arteries.

Transfusion to replace blood loss
This process is required under three conditions: -

Excessive destruction of red blood cells
Excessive blood loss
Inadequate production of red blood cells.

Home Remedies for Dengue
There are many types of remedies available to choose from when it comes to home remedies. They have been into tradition for years and is easily accessible to many. Though these remedies are only useful in curing the disease at its initial stage, you must know about some for an early rescue. You can also use Odomos natural mosquito repellent cream or mosquito repellent gel for protection from mosquitoes.

Giloy
Papaya Leaves
Fenugreek Leaves
Goldenseal
Neem Leaves
Basil Leaves

Giloy
This magical herb helps patient in maintaining the metabolic rate and improving the immune system. You can simply boil its stem and drink it as an herbal drink or can even add Tulsi leaves in it.

Papaya Leaves
It is known as one of the most important remedies for fighting the dengue fever as it shows immediate effects. Nutrients such as vitamin C aids to stimulate immunity and helps in increasing the platelets count and antioxidants in body. The leaves also help in removing toxins from the body.
To make juice from papaya leaves, simply cut the leaves and soak it in cold water. Grind the leaves and drink it four times in a day.
Drinking the juice of papaya leaves must be avoided during pregnancy.
Fenugreek Leaves
These leaves help in reducing fever and minimizing the pain.
They can be soaked into water and then blended to make juice out of it.
You can also add methi powder into the juice.
Goldenseal
This North American herb help in headaches, nausea and fever with an antiviral property to fight against dengue fever.

Neem Leaves
It has always been famous for its bacterial properties but apart from that, neem leaves also help in improving the blood platelet count. Continuous use of it helps in enhancing immunity.
Soak fresh neem leaves in cold water, filter them and drink it four times a day.
Drinking of this juice must be avoided during pregnancy and diabetes.
Basil Leaves
These leaves have antibacterial properties and promote good circulation as it helps in releasing sweat.
Boil 10 to 15 Basil leaves in water, cool it and drink the basil water for at least 2 to 3 times in a day.
Avoid this mixture if you are suffering from low blood pressure."

</item>
        <item>"SYMPTOMS
1.Cough
2.Production of mucus (sputum), which can be clear, white, yellowish-gray or green in color — rarely, it may be streaked with blood
3.Fatigue
4.Shortness of breath
5.Slight fever and chills
6.Chest discomfort

REMEDIES
Drink fluids but avoid caffeine and alcohol.
Get plenty of rest.
Take over-the-counter pain relievers to reduce inflammation, ease pain, and lower your fever. These could include acetaminophen (1 brand name: Tylenol) or ibuprofen (1 brand name: Advil). Never give aspirin to a ild. It has been linked to Reye syndrome, which can affect the liver and brain.
Increase the humidity in your home or use a humidifier."
</item>
        <item>"SYMPTOMS
1.Red, swollen tonsils
2.White or yellow coating or patches on the tonsils
3.Sore throat
4.Difficult or painful swallowing
5.Fever
6.Enlarged, tender glands (lymph nodes) in the neck
7.A scratchy, muffled or throaty voice
8.Bad breath
9.Stomachache, particularly in younger children
10.Stiff neck
11.Headache

REMEDIES
1.Salt water gargling
Gargling and rinsing with warm salt water can help sooth a sore throat and pain caused by tonsillitis. It can also reduce inflammation, and may even help to treat infections.

Stir about ½ teaspoon of salt in about 4 ounces of warm water. Stir until the salt is dissolved. Gargle and swish through the mouth for several seconds and then spit it out. You can rinse with regular water.

2. Licorice lozenges
Lozenges can help to soothe the throat, but they’re not all created equal. Some lozenges will contain ingredients with natural anti-inflammatory properties, or ingredients that can soothe pain on their own. Lozenges containing licorice as an ingredient can have strong anti-inflammatory benefits, soothing both discomfort and swelling in the tonsils and throat.

Lozenges shouldn’t be given to young children due to the choking risk. Instead, throat sprays are often a much better choice for children of this age. If you’re unsure, call their pediatrician.

You can shop for licorice lozenges on Amazon.


3. Warm tea with raw honey
Warm beverages like tea can help to reduce discomfort that can occur as a result of tonsillitis. Raw honey, often added to tea, has strong antibacterial properties, and may help to treat the infections causing the tonsillitis.

Drink tea warm instead of hot, and stir in the honey until dissolved. Certain teas may strengthen the benefits of this home remedy. Ginger tea, for example, is a strong anti-inflammatory, as is fennel tea, which can help to reduce inflammation and discomfort.

4. Popsicles and ice chips
Cold can be highly effective in treating pain, inflammation, and swelling that often comes with tonsillitis. Popsicles, frozen drinks like ICEEs, and frozen foods like ice cream can be particularly helpful to young children who can’t use other home remedies safely. Older children and adults can also suck on ice chips.



5. Humidifiers
Humidifiers can help to relieve the sore throat if the air is dry, or you’re experiencing dry mouth as a result of the tonsillitis. Dry air can irritate the throat, and humidifiers can help sooth discomfort in the throat and tonsils by adding moisture back into the air. Cool-mist humidifiers are most beneficial, especially when viruses are the cause of the tonsillitis.

Keep your humidifier on as needed, especially when you sleep at night, until the tonsillitis subsides. If you don’t have a humidifier and want fast relief, sitting in a room filled with steam from the shower can also provide humidity that can reduce symptoms.
"

</item>
        <item>"SYMPTOMS
1.Swelling
2.Tenderness
3.Bruising
4.Pain
5.Inability to put weight on the affected ankle
6.Skin discoloration
7.Stiffness

Self-care
For self-care of an ankle sprain, use the R.I.C.E. approach for the first two or three days:

Rest. Avoid activities that cause pain, swelling or discomfort.
Ice. Use an ice pack or ice slush bath immediately for 15 to 20 minutes and repeat every two to three hours while you're awake. If you have vascular disease, diabetes or decreased sensation, talk with your doctor before applying ice.
Compression. To help stop swelling, compress the ankle with an elastic bandage until the swelling stops. Don't hinder circulation by wrapping too tightly. Begin wrapping at the end farthest from your heart.
Elevation. To reduce swelling, elevate your ankle above the level of your heart, especially at night. Gravity helps reduce swelling by draining excess fluid.
Medications
In most cases, over-the-counter pain relievers — such as ibuprofen (Advil, Motrin IB, others) or naproxen sodium (Aleve, others) or acetaminophen (Tylenol, others) — are enough to manage the pain of a sprained ankle."

</item>
        <item>"SYMPTOMS
Urinating often
Feeling very thirsty
Feeling very hungry - even though you are eating
Extreme fatigue
Blurry vision
Cuts/bruises that are slow to heal
Weight loss - even though you are eating more (type 1)
Tingling, pain, or numbness in the hands/feet (type 2)

REMEDIES

1.Exercise Regularly
Regular exercise can help you lose weight and increase insulin sensitivity.

Increased insulin sensitivity means your cells are better able to use the available sugar in your bloodstream.

Exercise also helps your muscles use blood sugar for energy and muscle contraction.

If you have problems with blood sugar control, you should routinely check your levels. This will help you learn how you respond to different activities and keep your blood sugar levels from getting either too high or too low (2).

Good forms of exercise include weight lifting, brisk walking, running, biking, dancing, hiking, swimming and more.
BOTTOM LINE:
Exercise increases insulin sensitivity and helps your muscles pick up sugars from the blood. This can lead to reduced blood sugar levels.

2. Control Your Carb Intake
Your body breaks carbs down into sugars (mostly glucose), and then insulin moves the sugars into cells.

When you eat too many carbs or have problems with insulin function, this process fails and blood glucose levels rise.

However, there are several things you can do about this.

The American Diabetes Association (ADA) recommends controlling carb intake by counting carbs or using a food exchange system (3).

Some studies find that these methods can also help you plan your meals appropriately, which may further improve blood sugar control (4, 5).

Many studies also show that a low-carb diet helps reduce blood sugar levels and prevent blood sugar spikes (6, 7, 8, 9).

What's more, a low-carb diet can help control blood sugar levels in the long run (10).

You can read more in this article on healthy low-carb eating with diabetes.
BOTTOM LINE:
Carbs are broken down into glucose, which raises blood sugar levels. Reducing carbohydrate intake can help with blood sugar control.

3. Increase Your Fiber Intake
Fiber slows carb digestion and sugar absorption. For these reasons, it promotes a more gradual rise in blood sugar levels.

Furthermore, the type of fiber you eat may play a role.

There are two kinds of fiber: insoluble and soluble. While both are important, soluble fiber specifically has been shown to lower blood sugar levels (11, 12, 13).

Additionally, a high-fiber diet can help manage type 1 diabetes by improving blood sugar control and reducing blood sugar lows (13, 14).

Foods that are high in fiber include vegetables, fruits, legumes and whole grains.

The recommended daily intake of fiber is about 25 grams for women and 38 grams for men. That's about 14 grams for every 1,000 calories (15).
BOTTOM LINE:
Eating plenty of fiber can help with blood sugar control, and soluble dietary fiber is the most effective.

4. Drink Water and Stay Hydrated
Drinking enough water may help you keep your blood sugar levels within healthy limits.

In addition to preventing dehydration, it helps your kidneys flush out the excess blood sugar through urine.

One observational study showed that those who drank more water had a lower risk of developing high blood sugar levels (16).

Drinking water regularly re-hydrates the blood, lowers blood sugar levels and reduces diabetes risk (16, 17, 18, 19)
Keep in mind that water and other non-caloric beverages are best. Sugar-sweetened drinks raise blood glucose, drive weight gain and increase diabetes risk (20, 21).
BOTTOM LINE:
Staying hydrated can reduce blood sugar levels and help prevent diabetes. Water is best.


5. Implement Portion Control
Portion control helps regulate calorie intake and can lead to weight loss (22, 23, 24).

Consequently, controlling your weight promotes healthy blood sugar levels and has been shown to reduce the risk of developing type 2 diabetes (22, 23, 25, 26, 27, 28).

Monitoring your serving sizes also helps reduce calorie intake and subsequent blood sugar spikes (23, 24).

Here are some helpful tips for controlling portions:

Measure and weigh portions.
Use smaller plates.
Avoid all-you-can-eat restaurants.
Read food labels and check the serving sizes.
Keep a food journal.
Eat slowly.
BOTTOM LINE:
The more control you have over your serving sizes the better control you will have over your blood sugar levels.

6. Choose Foods With a Low Glycemic Index
The glycemic index was developed to assess the body's blood sugar response to foods that contain carbs (29).

Both the amount and type of carbs determine how a food affects blood sugar levels (30, 31).

Eating low-glycemic-index foods has been shown to reduce long-term blood sugar levels in type 1 and type 2 diabetics (32, 33).

Although the glycemic index of foods is important, the amount of carbs consumed also matters (34, 35).

Foods with a low glycemic index include seafood, meat, eggs, oats, barley, beans, lentils, legumes, sweet potatoes, corn, yams, most fruits and non-starchy vegetables.
BOTTOM LINE:
It's important to choose foods with a low glycemic index and watch your overall carb intake.

7. Control Stress Levels
Stress can affect your blood sugar levels (36, 37).

Hormones such as glucagon and cortisol are secreted during stress. These hormones cause blood sugar levels to go up (38, 39).

One study showed that exercise, relaxation and meditation significantly reduced stress and lowered blood sugar levels for students (40).

Exercises and relaxation methods like yoga and mindfulness-based stress reduction can also correct insulin secretion problems in chronic diabetes (40, 41, 42, 43, 44).
BOTTOM LINE:
Controlling stress levels through exercise or relaxation methods such as yoga will help you control blood sugars.

8. Monitor Your Blood Sugar Levels
"What gets measured gets managed."

Measuring and monitoring blood glucose levels can also help you control them.

For example, keeping track helps you determine whether you need to make adjustments in meals or medications (31).

It will also help you find out how your body reacts to certain foods (45, 46).

Try measuring your levels every day, and keeping track of the numbers in a log.
BOTTOM LINE:
Checking your sugars and maintaining a log every day will help you adjust foods and medications to decrease your sugar levels.

9. Get Enough Quality Sleep
Getting enough sleep feels great and is necessary for good health (47).

Poor sleeping habits and a lack of rest also affect blood sugar levels and insulin sensitivity. They can increase appetite and promote weight gain (48, 49).

Sleep deprivation decreases the release of growth hormones and increases cortisol levels. Both of these play an important role in blood sugar control (47, 50, 51).

Furthermore, good sleep is about both quantity and quality. It is best to get a sufficient amount of high-quality sleep every night (49).
BOTTOM LINE:
Good sleep helps maintain blood sugar control and promote a healthy weight. Poor sleep can disrupt important metabolic hormones.

10. Eat Foods Rich in Chromium and Magnesium
High blood sugar levels and diabetes have also been linked to micronutrient deficiencies (31, 52).

Examples include deficiencies in the minerals chromium and magnesium.

Chromium is involved in carb and fat metabolism. It also helps control blood sugar levels, and a lack of chromium may predispose you to carb intolerance (53, 54, 55).

However, the mechanisms behind this are not completely known. Studies also report mixed findings.

Two studies of diabetes patients showed that chromium had benefits for long-term blood sugar control. However, another study showed no benefits (55, 56, 57).

Chromium-rich foods include egg yolks, whole-grain products, high-bran cereals, coffee, nuts, green beans, broccoli and meat.

Magnesium has also been shown to benefit blood sugar levels, and magnesium deficiency has been linked to a higher risk of developing diabetes (31, 58, 59).

In one study, people with the highest magnesium intake had a 47% lower risk of becoming diabetic (60).

However, if you already eat plenty of magnesium-rich foods, then you probably will not benefit from supplements (61).

Magnesium-rich foods include dark leafy greens, whole grains, fish, dark chocolate, bananas, avocados and beans.
BOTTOM LINE:
Eating foods rich in chromium and magnesium on a regular basis can help prevent deficiencies and reduce blood sugar problems.

11. Try Apple Cider Vinegar
Apple cider vinegar has many benefits for your health.

It promotes lower fasting blood sugar levels, possibly by decreasing its production by the liver or increasing its use by cells (62, 63, 64).

What's more, studies show that vinegar significantly influences your body's response to sugars and improves insulin sensitivity (63, 65, 66, 67, 68, 69).

To incorporate apple cider vinegar into your diet, you can add it to salad dressings or mix 2 teaspoons in 8 ounces of water.

However, it's important to check with your doctor before taking apple cider vinegar if you are already taking medications that lower blood sugar.
BOTTOM LINE:
Adding apple cider vinegar to your diet can help your body in many ways, including reducing blood sugar levels.

12. Experiment With Cinnamon Extract
Cinnamon is known to have many health benefits.

For one, it has been shown to improve insulin sensitivity by decreasing insulin resistance at the cellular level (70, 71).

Studies show cinnamon can also lower blood sugar levels by up to 29% (72, 73, 74).

It slows the breakdown of carbs in the digestive tract, which moderates the rise in blood sugar after a meal (75, 76).

Cinnamon also acts in a similar way as insulin, although at a much slower rate (77).

An effective dose is 1–6 grams of cinnamon per day, or about 0.5–2 teaspoons (78).

However, definitely don't take more than that since too much cinnamon can be harmful. If you would like to try it, Amazon has a good selection available.
BOTTOM LINE:
Cinnamon has been shown to reduce fasting blood sugar levels and improve insulin sensitivity.

13. Try Berberine
Berberine is the active component of a Chinese herb that's been used to treat diabetes for thousands of years.

Berberine has been shown to help lower blood sugar and enhance the breakdown of carbs for energy (79, 80, 81).

What's more, berberine may be as effective as some blood sugar lowering drugs. This makes it one of the most effective supplements for those with diabetes or pre-diabetes (79, 82).

However, many of the mechanisms behind its effects are still unknown (81, 83).

Additionally, it may have some side effects. Diarrhea, constipation, flatulence and abdominal pain have been reported (84).

A common dosage protocol for berberine is 1,500 mg per day, taken before meals as 3 doses of 500 mg.

You can read more about this impressive supplement here: Berberine - The World's Most Effective Supplement?
BOTTOM LINE:
Berberine works well for lowering blood sugar levels and can help manage diabetes. However, it may have some digestive side effects.

14. Eat Fenugreek Seeds
Fenugreek seeds are a great source of soluble fiber, which can help control blood sugar levels.

Many studies have shown that fenugreek can effectively lower blood sugar in diabetics. It also helps reduce fasting glucose and improve glucose tolerance (85, 86, 87, 88).

Although not that popular, fenugreek can easily be added to baked goods to help treat diabetes. You can also make fenugreek flour or brew it into tea (89).

Fenugreek seeds are also considered one of the safest herbs for diabetes (87, 88).

The recommended dose of fenugreek seeds is 2–5 grams per day. If you'd like to try it, Amazon has a large selection available.
BOTTOM LINE:
Consider giving fenugreek seeds a try. They are easy to add to your diet and can help regulate blood glucose levels.

15. Lose Some Weight
It's a no-brainer that maintaining a healthy weight will improve your health and prevent future health problems.

Weight control also promotes healthy blood sugar levels and has been shown to reduce your risk of developing diabetes.

Even a 7% reduction in body weight can decrease your risk of developing diabetes by up to 58%, and it seems to work even better than medication (90).

What's more, these decreased risks can be sustained over the years (91, 92, 93).

You should also be conscious of your waistline, as it is perhaps the most important weight-related factor for estimating your diabetes risk.

A measurement of 35 inches (88.9 cm) or more for women and 40 inches (101.6 cm) or more for men is associated with an increased risk of developing insulin resistance, high blood sugar levels and type 2 diabetes (94).

Having a healthy waist measurement may be even more important than your overall weight (94).
BOTTOM LINE:
Keeping a healthy weight and waistline will help you maintain normal blood sugar levels and decrease your risk of developing diabetes."
</item>
        <item>"SYMPTOMS
1.Severe headache
2.Fatigue or confusion
3.Vision problems
4.Chest pain
5.Difficulty breathing
6.Irregular heartbeat
7.Blood in the urine
8.Pounding in your chest, neck, or ears

REMEDIES
1.Lose extra pounds and watch your waistline
Blood pressure often increases as weight increases. Being overweight also can cause disrupted breathing while you sleep (sleep apnea), which further raises your blood pressure.

Weight loss is one of the most effective lifestyle changes for controlling blood pressure. Losing even a small amount of weight if you're overweight or obese can help reduce your blood pressure. In general, you may reduce your blood pressure by about 1 millimeter of mercury (mm Hg) with each kilogram (about 2.2 pounds) of weight you lose.

Besides shedding pounds, you generally should also keep an eye on your waistline. Carrying too much weight around your waist can put you at greater risk of high blood pressure.

In general:

Men are at risk if their waist measurement is greater than 40 inches (102 centimeters).
Women are at risk if their waist measurement is greater than 35 inches (89 centimeters).
These numbers vary among ethnic groups. Ask your doctor about a healthy waist measurement for you.

2. Exercise regularly
Regular physical activity — such as 150 minutes a week, or about 30 minutes most days of the week — can lower your blood pressure by about 5 to 8 mm Hg if you have high blood pressure. It's important to be consistent because if you stop exercising, your blood pressure can rise again.

If you have elevated blood pressure, exercise can help you avoid developing hypertension. If you already have hypertension, regular physical activity can bring your blood pressure down to safer levels.

Some examples of aerobic exercise you may try to lower blood pressure include walking, jogging, cycling, swimming or dancing. You can also try high-intensity interval training, which involves alternating short bursts of intense activity with subsequent recovery periods of lighter activity. Strength training also can help reduce blood pressure. Aim to include strength training exercises at least two days a week. Talk to your doctor about developing an exercise program.

3. Eat a healthy diet
Eating a diet that is rich in whole grains, fruits, vegetables and low-fat dairy products and skimps on saturated fat and cholesterol can lower your blood pressure by up to 11 mm Hg if you have high blood pressure. This eating plan is known as the Dietary Approaches to Stop Hypertension (DASH) diet.

It isn't easy to change your eating habits, but with these tips, you can adopt a healthy diet:

Keep a food diary. Writing down what you eat, even for just a week, can shed surprising light on your true eating habits. Monitor what you eat, how much, when and why.
Consider boosting potassium. Potassium can lessen the effects of sodium on blood pressure. The best source of potassium is food, such as fruits and vegetables, rather than supplements. Talk to your doctor about the potassium level that's best for you.
Be a smart shopper. Read food labels when you shop and stick to your healthy-eating plan when you're dining out, too.

4. Reduce sodium in your diet
Even a small reduction in the sodium in your diet can improve your heart health and reduce blood pressure by about 5 to 6 mm Hg if you have high blood pressure.

The effect of sodium intake on blood pressure varies among groups of people. In general, limit sodium to 2,300 milligrams (mg) a day or less. However, a lower sodium intake — 1,500 mg a day or less — is ideal for most adults.

To decrease sodium in your diet, consider these tips:

Read food labels. If possible, choose low-sodium alternatives of the foods and beverages you normally buy.
Eat fewer processed foods. Only a small amount of sodium occurs naturally in foods. Most sodium is added during processing.
Don't add salt. Just 1 level teaspoon of salt has 2,300 mg of sodium. Use herbs or spices to add flavor to your food.
Ease into it. If you don't feel you can drastically reduce the sodium in your diet suddenly, cut back gradually. Your palate will adjust over time.

5. Limit the amount of alcohol you drink
Alcohol can be both good and bad for your health. By drinking alcohol only in moderation — generally one drink a day for women, or two a day for men — you can potentially lower your blood pressure by about 4 mm Hg. One drink equals 12 ounces of beer, five ounces of wine or 1.5 ounces of 80-proof liquor.

But that protective effect is lost if you drink too much alcohol.

Drinking more than moderate amounts of alcohol can actually raise blood pressure by several points. It can also reduce the effectiveness of blood pressure medications.

6. Quit smoking
Each cigarette you smoke increases your blood pressure for many minutes after you finish. Stopping smoking helps your blood pressure return to normal. Quitting smoking can reduce your risk of heart disease and improve your overall health. People who quit smoking may live longer than people who never quit smoking.

7. Cut back on caffeine
The role caffeine plays in blood pressure is still debated. Caffeine can raise blood pressure up to 10 mm Hg in people who rarely consume it. But people who drink coffee regularly may experience little or no effect on their blood pressure.

Although the long-term effects of caffeine on blood pressure aren't clear, it's possible blood pressure may slightly increase.

To see if caffeine raises your blood pressure, check your pressure within 30 minutes of drinking a caffeinated beverage. If your blood pressure increases by 5 to 10 mm Hg, you may be sensitive to the blood pressure raising effects of caffeine. Talk to your doctor about the effects of caffeine on your blood pressure.

8. Reduce your stress
Chronic stress may contribute to high blood pressure. More research is needed to determine the effects of chronic stress on blood pressure. Occasional stress also can contribute to high blood pressure if you react to stress by eating unhealthy food, drinking alcohol or smoking.

Take some time to think about what causes you to feel stressed, such as work, family, finances or illness. Once you know what's causing your stress, consider how you can eliminate or reduce stress.

If you can't eliminate all of your stressors, you can at least cope with them in a healthier way. Try to:

Change your expectations. For example, plan your day and focus on your priorities. Avoid trying to do too much and learn to say no. Understand there are some things you can't change or control, but you can focus on how you react to them.
Focus on issues you can control and make plans to solve them. If you are having an issue at work, try talking to your manager. If you are having a conflict with your kids or spouse, take steps to resolve it.
Avoid stress triggers. Try to avoid triggers when you can. For example, if rush-hour traffic on the way to work causes stress, try leaving earlier in the morning, or take public transportation. Avoid people who cause you stress if possible.
Make time to relax and to do activities you enjoy. Take time each day to sit quietly and breathe deeply. Make time for enjoyable activities or hobbies in your schedule, such as taking a walk, cooking or volunteering.
Practice gratitude. Expressing gratitude to others can help reduce your stress.

9. Monitor your blood pressure at home and see your doctor regularly
Home monitoring can help you keep tabs on your blood pressure, make certain your lifestyle changes are working, and alert you and your doctor to potential health complications. Blood pressure monitors are available widely and without a prescription. Talk to your doctor about home monitoring before you get started.

Regular visits with your doctor are also key to controlling your blood pressure. If your blood pressure is well-controlled, check with your doctor about how often you need to check it. Your doctor may suggest checking it daily or less often. If you're making any changes in your medications or other treatments, your doctor may recommend you check your blood pressure starting two weeks after treatment changes and a week before your next appointment.

10. Get support
Supportive family and friends can help improve your health. They may encourage you to take care of yourself, drive you to the doctor's office or embark on an exercise program with you to keep your blood pressure low.

If you find you need support beyond your family and friends, consider joining a support group. This may put you in touch with people who can give you an emotional or morale boost and who can offer practical tips to cope with your condition."</item>
        <item>"SYMPTOMS
1.Abdominal cramps
2.Abdominal pains
3.Urgency to go to the toilet
4.Frequent passing of loose, watery faeces
5.Nausea
6.Vomiting.

REMEDIES
1.Drink Water for Diarrhoea
First things first, you must, by all means, drink enough water and stay hydrated. You will lose a lot of fluid when suffering from diarrhoea along with electrolytes. You have to replace them by drinking plenty of fluids. You must also drink sports drinks such as Gatorade to get renewed energy. You can also have fruit juices other than apple and prune. Staying hydrated during a bout of diarrhoea is a must.

2.Eat Starchy Foods for Diarrhoea
By eating precooked rice or tapioca, cereals could help to ease your tummy. You can avoid adding too much of sugar or salt in these foods as you can aggravate diarrhoea. You could also prevent oatmeal as it is high on fiber and your intestines cannot tolerate the added bulk. Go for potatoes as they restore nutrients and comfort your stomach, but this doesn’t mean that you go on eating potato chips or fries, fried foods are a strict no-no. Cooked white rice is another option for starchy food.

3.Eat Yogurt for Diarrhoea
Your diarrhoea can be eased with the help of yogurt, but here we aren’t talking about plain yogurts. You will need to eat those that have live bacterial cultures such as Lactobacillus acidophilus and Bifidobacterium. These will help to restore the good bacteria in your intestine by producing lactic acid, thereby destroying the harmful bacteria that are causing diarrhoea. You could add a banana with your yogurt for added benefit.

4.Use Apples for Diarrhoea
Cook approximately one to two apples till the time they are mushy, and then subsequently add one teaspoon ghee, a pinch of cardamom, and a pinch of nutmeg. This mixture is a deliciously rich remedy to fight diarrhoea.
Use Cooked Rice with Yogurt for Diarrhoea
Another efficient remedy for diarrhoea is cooked rice with yogurt. Take about a cupful of cooked basmati rice, add 1 tablespoon of ghee and 3 or 4 tablespoons of plain fresh yogurt, stir together, and eat.

5.Drink Chamomile Tea for Diarrhoea
Chamomile tea is good because it has antispasmodic properties that can provide relief from many other kinds of intestinal disorders, also helping in the treatment of intestinal inflammation. You should make chamomile tea by steeping a teaspoon of chamomile flowers and one teaspoon of peppermint leaves in a cup of boiling water for about 10 minutes. Drink this tea after straining it at least thrice a day.

You must start eating mild foods as soon as your stomach starts to feel better, and avoid chewing gums that contain sorbitol. Also, you must avoid dairy products for some time which includes during and after the phase of diarrhoea
"
</item>
        <item>"SYMPTOMS
1.Abdominal pain,
2.Heartburn or acid indigestion (acid reflux),
3.Bloating,
4.Gas
5.Nausea
6.Acidic taste in the mouth
7.Stomach discomfort
8.Constipation or diarrhea
9.Decreased appetite.

REMEDIES

1.Basil Leaves
The soothing and carminative properties of basil leaves can give you instant relief from acidity. At the first sign of gas, eat a few basil leaves or boil 3-4 basil leaves in a cup of water and let it simmer for a few minutes. Sip on it frequently. This is one of the best home remedies for acidity.
Basil leaves have soothing and carminative properties

2. Fennel
You can also “chew sauf after meals, to prevent stomach acidity”, advises Nutritionist Anshul Jaibharat. “For its multitude of gastrointestinal benefits, fennel tea is sure to help the digestive tract be healthy and happy. The tea is considered very useful to help indigestion and bloating because of the oils found in these seeds”, according to Shilpa Arora ND, a renowned Health Practitioner, Nutritionist and certified Macrobiotic Health Coach.
Fennel tea is sure to help the digestive tract be healthy and happy

3. Cinnamon
This humble spice works as a natural antacid for stomach acidity and can settle your stomach, by improving digestion and absorption. For relief, drink cinnamon tea to heal infections in the gastrointestinal tract. Cinnamon is a powerhouse of nutrients and loaded with health benefiting properties.
This humble spice works as a natural antacid

4. Buttermilk
Did you know that buttermilk is categorised as a sattvic food in Ayurveda? So, the next time you get acidity after eating a heavy or spicy meal, skip the antacid and drink a glass of chaas instead. Buttermilk contains lactic acid that normalizes acidity in the stomach. Sprinkle a dash of black pepper or 1 teaspoon of ground coriander leaves for best results.
Buttermilk contains lactic acid that normalises acidity in the stomach​

5. Jaggery
Ever wondered why our elders finish a meal with gur? “Due to its high magnesium content, jaggery helps boost intestinal strength”, says Dr. Manoj K. Ahuja, Fortis Hospital, New Delhi. It aids digestion and makes your digestive system more alkaline in nature, thus reducing stomach acidity. Suck on a small piece of gur after a meal, and reap the benefits. Since jaggery also helps maintain normal body temperature, cooling the stomach - experts recommend drinking Gur Sharbat (jaggery soaked in ice cold water) during the summer.
Jaggery aids digestion and makes your digestive system more alkaline in nature

6. Cloves
Over the years, cloves have grabbed a prominent place in traditional Chinese medicine and Ayurveda to treat digestive disorders. Cloves are carminative in nature, thus preventing the formation of gas in the gastrointestinal tract. Add cloves while cooking foods like kidney beans or black gram that tend to cause flatulence. You can even eat crushed cloves and cardamom (mixed in equal amounts) to treat acidity, and get rid of bad breath (which often accompanies this problem).
Cloves have grabbed a prominent place in traditional Chinese medicine and Ayurveda

7. Cumin Seeds
Cumin seeds work as a great acid neutralizer, aid digestion and relieve stomach pain. Slightly crush some roasted cumin seeds, stir it into a glass of water or steep one teaspoon of cumin seeds in a cup of boiled water and drink it after every meal.

8. Ginger
Beneath its knobbly exterior, ginger hides many health benefits. “Ginger has excellent digestive and anti-inflammatory properties”, says Dr. Ahuja, Fortis Hospital. To help neutralize stomach acids, you can chew a slice of fresh ginger, or have a spoonful of ginger juice two-three times a day, or steep fresh ginger in a cup of boiling water and drink up.
Beneath its knobbly exterior, ginger hides many health benefits

9. Cold Milk
For those who are not lactose intolerant, milk can help stabilize gastric acids in the stomach. It is rich in calcium, which prevents the buildup of acid in the stomach. “All you need to do is drink a glass of cold milk the next time you suffer from acidity”, suggests Nutritionist Anshul Jaibharat.
Milk is rich in calcium, which prevents the buildup of acid in the stomach

10. Apple Cider Vinegar
Very often, your acid reflux is in fact the result of too little stomach acid. That’s where apple cider vinegar steps in. Simply mix 1-2 teaspoons of raw, unfiltered apple cider vinegar in a cup of water and drink it once or twice a day. You can also take a tablespoon of apple cider vinegar, and chase it with a glass of water.

11. Coconut Water
“When you drink coconut water, your body's pH acidic level turns alkaline”, adds Dr. Ahuja, Fortis Hospital. It also helps produce mucous in your stomach, which protects the stomach from harmful effects of excessive acid production. Since it is rich in fibre, it aids digestion and prevents the re-occurrence of acidity.

12. Banana
When it comes to health benefiting properties, bananas hold much importance. Bananas contain natural antacids that can act as a buffer against acid reflux. This is the simplest home remedy for getting rid of acidity. Eat one banana every day to prevent discomfort.
Bananas contain natural antacids that can act as a buffer against acid reflux
So if you ever happen to suffer from acidity, then bring these home remedies to your rescue."
</item>
        <item>"SYMPTOMS
1.Coughing that lasts three or more weeks
2.Coughing up blood
3.Chest pain, or pain with breathing or coughing
4.Unintentional weight loss
5.Fatigue
6.Fever
7.Night sweats
8.Chills
9.Loss of appetite

REMEDIES
Most common TB drugs
If you have latent tuberculosis, you may need to take only one or two types of TB drug. Active tuberculosis, particularly if it's a drug-resistant strain, will require several drugs at once. The most common medications used to treat tuberculosis include:

Isoniazid
Rifampin (Rifadin, Rimactane)
Ethambutol (Myambutol)
Pyrazinamide"
</item>



    </string-array>

</resources>